This land will be civilized.
The Proposition is a action, adventure, crime film directed by John Hillcoat.
In 1880s Australia, a lawman offers renegade Charlie Burns a difficult choice.
In order to save his younger brother from the gallows, Charlie must hunt down
and kill his older brother, who is wanted for rape and murder.
Venturing into one of the Outback's most inhospitable regions, Charlie
faces a terrible moral dilemma that can end only in violence.
Charlie Burns, played by Guy Pearce.
Captain Morris Stanley, played by Ray Winstone.
Arthur Burns, played by Danny Huston.
Martha Stanley, played by Emily Watson.
Eden Fletcher, played by David Wenham.
Mike Burns, played by Richard Wilson.
The Proposition is a 2005 Australian Western film directed by John
Hillcoat and written by screenwriter and musician Nick Cave.
It stars Guy Pearce, Ray Winstone, Emily Watson, John
Hurt, Danny Huston and David Wenham.
The film's production completed in 2004 and was followed by a wide 2005
release in Australia and a 2006 cinematic run in the U.S.
through First Look Pictures.
The film was shot on location in Winton, Queensland.
The film explores themes of australia, bounty
hunter, psychopath, gallows, outlaw.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.